This is Software Engineering Radio, the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SE-Radio.net.
SE Radio is brought to you by the IEEE
Computer Society and by IEEE Software
Magazine online at
computer.org/software.
Hi, this is Philip Winston for Software
Engineering Radio. My guest today is
Timothy Beamish. Timothy has been a
software developer for more than 20
years with a focus on front-end
architecture. He's currently a staff
engineer at BenchSci overseeing a suite
of front-end applications written in
React and Next.js.
Prior to BenchSci, he was a senior staff
engineer and web team lead at Plenty of
Fish, one of the largest online dating
sites. Welcome, Timothy. Is there
anything I left out of your bio?
No, I think that's good. Yeah, front-end
mostly focused, dipping into the
back-end a little bit, and yeah, built
tons of tons of websites over the last
few years.
Great. So, let me just set the stage for
the show a little bit. So, React is a
very popular open-source front-end
library, I'll say, released by Facebook
in 2013,
and Next.js is a framework for React
released by Vercel in 2016.
So, we're going to divide the show into
three parts. First, we'll talk a little
bit about React itself with an eye
towards the following discussions.
Then, we'll talk about Next.js and go
through a number of features and discuss
the advantages and some of the
disadvantages of Next.js.
And finally, we'll talk about a recent
migration to Next.js that Timothy
oversaw at his current company.
This part of the show is based on a blog
post of Timothy's called Moving House to
Next.js that we'll put a link into the
show notes.
I also wanted to mention that Timothy
and I both currently work at the same
company, although kind of at opposite
ends of the company, so we don't really
encounter each other
day-to-day.
Before we dive into React, I I to
highlight a previous Software
engineering episode that discussed React
in pretty good detail.
Episode 382, Michael Chan on learning
React JS. So, to start off, is React a
framework or a set of components or a
library? How would you characterize
React?
React is a framework for building
front-end applications. And it's
important to know that it only does one
thing and it does that one thing well.
It doesn't do everything. It doesn't
solve all the problems of the front-end.
Its job is to take uh data and represent
that as a state via UI. So, it's
just places a bunch of UI on the screen,
which is telling you what your data
situation is
currently in the front-end. As soon as
that data changes, the front-end
changes, the UI changes. And that's
pretty much all it does. There's lots of
other problems you have to solve on the
front-end and React doesn't solve any of
those for you,
which is what where kind of Next.js
comes in to help out a little bit. It
helps solve some of the other problems.
I saw the name React and looked it up
and it said it's kind of based on
reactive programming, which is kind of
what you were saying, the ability to
handle updates, the data updates to
otherwise static content. Is that
a fair characterization?
Yeah. So, in the days before React, in
fact, in the days of static web pages,
when the web was pretty boring, you'd go
to a web page, it would render. If you
wanted to go get some new information,
you'd have to render a whole new page
again.
Then Ajax came along and that blew up
the internet. And it it meant that web
pages didn't need to load in an entirety
to change themselves. They could
dynamically shift over time without
loading the whole page. Little pieces
could reach out and ask questions of
servers, get answers back, and re-render
just portions of the internet. And this
opened up web pages to be dynamic
applications. But it also creates a lot
of complexity because now you've got to
manage which parts of the page are
updated, what the state of different
parts of the page, different parts of
the page have to be in different types
of state. You have to have some sort of
global management system to handle all
that. And we had tools like jQuery to
help us kind of paint things on the
page, but it didn't it didn't help us
organize the data. And then things like
Angular and React came along as
solutions to this problem. And then for
a little while we had massive front-end
framework wars, and these days React
kind of stood out as the leading way to
do this, but basically it's just job is
to manage the data that's coming into
the application, the global state of the
application, and allow you to represent
that using UI. So it'll figure out which
parts of the pages need updating, which
parts don't, and you don't have to worry
about making sure that everything's in
sync. You just make sure that your
data's correct, and that you have a good
mapping to the UI.
One React concept is components. Are
these visual components you can point to
on the screen? Are they more generic
than that? What is a React component?
By and large, yeah, they would be visual
components, although not always. You can
have components that are hidden in the
background that don't actually render
anything. But generally speaking, a
component is a little piece of UI that
gets some data sent to it, or it holds
on to some internal data. When it gets
data sent to it, that's called a prop or
a property. And when it holds on to
internal data, that's called its its own
internal state.
And it'll render something to represent
the props and state that it has. So
maybe if it's if if the component is
meant to represent a button, and the
button needs to be red in some cases and
green in in other cases based on some
information coming into it, the
component's job is to say, "Hey, I take
a property that tells me whether I'm on
or off, and if I'm on I'm red, and if
I'm off I'm green." And the thing that
talks to me only has to know whether I'm
on or off. It doesn't have to know
anything about red or green. That's my
job to handle that on means red and off
means green. And I will take care of
that. All you make you you just make
sure that the data flowing into me is
tells me whether or not I should be on
or off. And that's kind of what a
component does. Now, you can have That's
That's probably like the simplest form
of component. There's a few different
types of components, and the
the more, I guess, trickier ones would
be things that have to fetch
asynchronous data to
update the application. So, some
components, their job is to say, "Hey, I
I need to get some data to to render
myself properly. We don't have it. I
need to go ask a server for some data."
So, it has to do uh some sort of
asynchronous operation. Then, it becomes
more complicated. It has to handle
things like, "Hey, I'm I'm asking for
data now, but I still need to render
something, so I need to render the fact
that I'm asking for data." So, I would
typically put like a loading
spinner on the uh page.
So, when we say render in this case with
web browsers, we're talking about
emitting like a chunk of HTML that's
going to fit into the page somewhere,
and then the browser renders it perhaps
at some rate, like
Yeah, rendering is painting pixels onto
the screen, and unfortunately, it tends
to be a rather expensive operation. So,
one of React's superpowers is that it
holds on to a copy of what the UI looks
like in the background. That's And it's
called the the the shadow DOM.
And React is able to update the shadow
DOM. The shadow DOM is like a giant
tree. So, it'll update a piece of that
tree, and it knows that the stuff that's
on the screen is one tree, my shadow DOM
is another tree, they should be in sync,
and I know that because I've just
updated my shadow DOM, there's a little
piece of it that's now out of sync with
what's on the screen. I need to repaint
just that little piece. So, I don't need
to repaint every pixel on the screen. I
just repaint that one little piece.
That's a big benefit because, as I said,
painting the screen is expensive. So, if
I only have to paint a little portion of
the screen, I'm doing much better, And
that's kind of where React superpower
comes in. So, it uses the shadow DOM to
figure out what parts of the real screen
do I need to paint, and then it does the
process of rendering, which is like you
said, putting pixels in the right color
in the right place on a screen.
And the DOM is the the document object
model that's kind of like the HTML tree.
Yes, exactly. So, if you crack open any
webpage in Chrome, you can hit F12 and
go into your developer tools and look at
how a webpage is built. It is in a
document, which is structured in what's
called a a DOM, which stands for
document object model, and it's
basically a tree. So, it starts at the
very root, and the very first tag will
be your HTML tag, and then that tag will
have That's the root of your tree. It'll
have some children. Typically, the first
two children that it has is a head child
and a body child. Although, it doesn't
necessarily have to have that. You could
have some more things. And then, in your
head child, there's information that
represents kind of metadata about the
document. And then, in your body child
is kind of the representation of what
you see on the screen. And so, that's
all split up into HTML tags, and those
tags organize the structure of the
document. And then, CSS is Cascading
Style Sheets is the technology that
decides what that structure is meant to
look like in terms of what colors and
formatting and things has. And React
organizes all of that for you. So,
instead of thinking about it in terms of
HTML elements and CSS tags on things and
CSS attributes on things, you you think
of it in terms of components, which are
building blocks that still live in a
hierarchical tree-like structure, and
they have styling glued into them, and
they get represented in the ethereal
world of React. They get updated in in
the shadow DOM, and then React says,
"Hey, my shadow DOM's changed. I now
have to go repaint different HTML on on
the front end."
How about JSX, JavaScript syntax
extension? I think that's not specific
to React, but maybe it's used with
React. Have you used that?
Yes, it's funny because so we write
React using JavaScript and when you use
the JSX extension, it looks like you're
writing HTML inside of JavaScript which
kind of breaks your brain a little bit,
but that's not actually what's
happening. I would say JSX is an
extension of JavaScript is a better way
of saying it. It allows you to write
what looks like HTML inside your
JavaScript program. So normally in
regular JavaScript syntax, you can't
define a piece of HTML and assign it to
a variable. You'd have to you'd have to
write the HTML in a string and your and
the content of your variable is actually
a string. With JSX, you can write a
component which uses a similar type of
syntax as you would see in HTML and that
actually becomes the content of your
variable. Under the hood, it's actually
just building classes and passing around
functions that produce classes. But JSX
allows you to abstract that away and so
visually, you look and feel like you're
building an HTML-like document using
tags and attributes when in reality
under the hood, it's getting transformed
into a functions and and classes.
Since React came out of Facebook, I
think I would imagine one of the
benefits of components is being able to
have a bigger team work on a single
application, but maybe have components
that are reused. Is that part of the
benefit of React that it can enable this
kind of reuse?
Yes, absolutely. You hit on a a great
point. So in the old days of HTML, if
you had a button on the top of the
screen and a button on the bottom of the
screen and they looked the same, but
they did different things, you'd have to
write that code out twice. With React,
you would make a single button component
which then you can use all over your
site, and that single button component,
I mean, you want it to do different
things in different situations, so you
would pass in some property to a
instance of that button to say, I want
you to execute this function when you
get clicked, and this other one, I'm
going to create you you look exactly
like the other one. I'm going to reuse
this component, but I'm going to pass in
another function to you to say that when
you get clicked, you do something
slightly different. So, yeah, it allows
for tremendous reuse, which helps you
organize your code base, makes you far
more efficient, and helps teams work
together much more efficiently.
Let's move on to Next.js, and we can
still reference React features to
compare them to Next.js or or just sort
of go between the two, but let's talk
about Next.js and and what it adds. I'm
going to start with this data fetching
and client-side rendering and
server-side rendering, just kind of
comparing those and which does Next.js
favor or which does it encourage or
which styles are are common.
Okay, so
Next.js doesn't necessarily solve the
problem of data fetching for you. So,
this is a pretty big problem in the
React ecosystem is is like I said, React
is good at you give it some data and it
renders it to the screen, but how do you
get the data in the first place? React
doesn't have an opinion on how you do
that. There's lots of different ways to
do that. Next.js doesn't necessarily
solve that problem, either. So, there's
lots of different ways to do data
fetching. And typically, data fetching
is when your software needs to know
something, so it reaches out to an
external server, usually an API server,
asks it a question via an HTTP request,
and gets back some data. And this is
kind of the principle of Ajax. This is
this is what kind of turned web 1.0 into
web 2.0. And there's lots of different
ways to do it in React. Probably the
most popular way is a library called
Axios, which it's an older library, but
it's bulletproof. It works in more
browsers, it has tons of features. The
new way, the future, is using an API
called fetch, the fetch API, which is
built into the browsers now, but more
people that I found are still using
Axios cuz it still has is a little more
feature rich and works in the weirdest
of of places. It's been around a little
longer. The old-school way of doing data
fetching is actually making XHR
requests, which is old and convoluted
and we now have lots of frameworks built
on top of that, so you don't have to
deal with actually like the guts of
Ajax, which is building XHR stuff. So,
the newest, coolest way of making data
fetching requests outside of Axios and
fetch is a is a framework that kind of
encompasses both of those and at
BenchSci we use something called React
Query. React Query is a library built
for React that is meant to handle your
data fetching stuff in a React context.
So, it uses this concept of hooks, which
is a newer React mechanism, where a
component will call a series of hooks,
one or more or zero, before it does its
rendering and those hooks are meant to
perform procedures and in one of those
procedures can invoke React Query, which
has a clever caching system built into
it and knows if I can't find something
in my cache, then I need to reach out to
an API server to get the information I
need and then I can send that back. So,
the output of the hook when you when you
you always call the hook when you render
the component, the output of the hook is
the contents of React Query, which is
either going to be go away, I'm loading
or here is some data for you or there's
been an error
happening. And so, your component then
either has the data it needs, it knows
what to do, or it can render a loading
state or it can render an error state.
So, I should mention React Query sits on
top of the Axio system or the fetch
system or if you really are crazy you
could do it with the old school XHR Ajax
system. And most people use
Axios as far as I've seen. So, let's
talk for a little bit just about where
the need for another framework came from
or how Next.js came to be or how you
came to discover Next.js and kind of
just from a high level what sort of
benefits does it provide? I think the
data fetching is an example of
There's a lot of choices there and a lot
of options, but just from like a high
level if I were considering using
Next.js what aspects of my project would
steer me in that direction? So, as I
said React only solves one part of the
front end problem scape and it does a
good job of that. Next.js comes along to
offer you some opinions on how to set up
a React application. And so it kind of
makes things a little more rigid and
concrete for you. So, one of the things
that it provides out of the box, which
is pretty nice, is a nice routing system
that's really easy to kind of understand
and comprehend. Routing is the
relationship between what is the address
in your URL like in in your browser in
that in that URL bar, what is that
address in relation to what is on the
page? So, we've now moved to single page
applications on the internet, which
means you when you load up a website and
you traverse through that website page
by page by page, you're not actually in
a lot of cases making full requests to
get back full web pages and render
those. What's happening is you're just
saying, "Hey, I want to travel through
this website and my state is just going
to update and change as I'm traveling
from place to place in this website."
The route needs to reflect that I am now
at this point in the web website. Now
I'm at this point. Now I'm at this
point. I need to have a route that
reflects that so that if I if I want to
leave this website and then come back to
to one part of it, I have a way of
getting there, which is what the route
is. I can bookmark that route, I can
save it, and I can call up this website
and get to that state again. So, routes
have now changed because in a
single-page application, you're not
necessarily downloading a whole new
page, you're downloading the first page,
and then you're transitioning your state
to be where it needs to be to be aligned
with whatever the route is. Does that
make sense?
Yes, I think so. So, at one point, the
URL corresponded strictly to
subdirectories in a file system, and if
we're running a single-page application,
that's no longer true, but the different
components of the URL still need to
point to something, but maybe they're
pointing to something within the
application.
You got it, right on. So, what Next.js
does is it helps solve the complexity of
the routing issue. Previous to Next.js,
I think the most popular library would
be React Router, which enables you to
build a routing system in your
application, and it's usually one of the
first things you do. So, yeah, I'm I'm
going to create a React app, and the
very first thing in your React app is
like your your top-level component, and
in there you will stick your your
routing system, which will say, "Okay,
I'm the very first component that loads
is my is my outer shell." It's usually
called the app component. And then,
somewhere pretty soon after that, I'm
going to define all my routes. So,
Next.js, this works, and it's nice.
Next.js says, "Hey, we're we're going to
offer you something a little different.
We're going to
because you're used to file folder
structures being represented as routes,
we're going to offer that back to you."
So, Next.js gives you the ability to
structure your Next.js app in your file
folder structure. You can have a a
folder for all of your different routes,
and your routes follow whatever that
file folder structure is, so that you
end up in your file folder structure, if
you have I meant subdirectory a/b/c
then that means that the page my website
/a/b/c
will be an actual page and you can stick
a page component in that folder
structure. Next.js will look at that
file folder structure. It'll extract out
the hierarchy of it and it'll turn it
into a set of react routes for you and
it'll paste it into the top level of
your app so you don't have to worry
about setting up routes programmatically
anymore. You just do it using your file
folder structure.
So we're talking about single page
applications but then in this case does
that imply it's it's multiple pages when
you're talking about the subdirectory
corresponding to a route? I guess I
guess just trying to understand is
single page application the most common
way or is it a required way to do sort
of Next.js apps?
Next.js applications.
Okay, this is interesting cuz in a
single page application technically
there is only one web page
but humans like to organize things as
when I click on a button and and I go
somewhere else I go somewhere else in
actuality what's happening is your state
in the application is changing. You're
not necessarily loading up a brand new
web page. You're still on the same web
page but you're you're seeing a
completely different state and to help
humans kind of resolve this we use the
terminology hey, you've gone to a new
page in the website but that's not
actually true. You haven't downloaded a
brand new page. You've just updated the
the the state in that page. So in the
olden days yeah, sure. You'd have to if
if you were to go to a/b/c you would be
downloading the C page and if you were
to go to a/b you're downloading the B
page.
That's not true here. So yes, we are
always on the same page. A single page
application is only ever one page. It
has to update its its state to get to
the right state which is aligned with
the route that you're on, the URL that
you're on, and all that is to help
humans kind of resolve the fact that
they think they're moving around to
different pages when in actuality
they're not. It's just a state update
happening in a single-page React app.
Maybe this is related, but I came across
a concept called dynamic routes. Is that
building on this, or is that a different
type of route?
Sometimes, let's say I I want to go to a
some ID  c.
So, let's say we're looking at a a
shopping cart or some sort of shopping
site.
And you want to look at all the products
in the winter section. So, the maybe you
want the URL to be products
winter  list. And that will list
all the products in the winter section
of this department store that you're
looking at. But maybe they have a summer
section, as well. So, maybe you want to
go to product  summer
list, and you'll get all the summer
products. Now, the list of summer
products and the list of winter
products, you could abstract them to say
that they're going to be really similar.
Like, it's a list of things, and some of
them are summer in one case, and some of
them are winter. So, the fact that that
you could flip summer and winter. So, so
summer and winter becomes this kind of
dynamic piece in a React app. You could
say that we're actually going to render
the exact same pages and exact same
components, and all we need to do is
change one little piece of data in the
back to say, "Hey, database, get me my
winter products, and I want to list
those, or get me my summer products, and
I want to list those."
And so, in the route up in the URL, the
dynamic piece is the variable that
represents winter and or summer. In
Next.js, you can do that by updating
your file folder structure and using a
special piece of syntax, just chucking
some square brackets around a folder to
indicate that that folder is going to
have a dynamic property about it. And
so, Next.js can easily say, "Oh, this is
a dynamic folder. I'm going to turn this
keyword that you used inside those
square brackets, the name of your
folder, I'm going to turn that into a
variable and I'm going to feed it into
whatever component is downstream from
this folder. So, when you load that
component up, it's going to get a
variable. Let's call it season. So,
maybe maybe you've named that folder
square bracket season ending square
bracket. Then your component's going to
get a season variable coming in and you
can assume the value of season is going
to be either winter or summer and if
it's not, you can throw up an error
saying you're you've picked the wrong
season. And if it's winter, then the
React component downstream from that is
going to ask the API, "Give me all the
winter products. If not, give me all the
summer products." And then it's going to
generically do the same thing. All I'm
doing is asking for a set of products
and I want to then render them to to the
screen.
So, with season, there's only four
seasons, but I think what you're saying
is that dynamic portion of the route
could correspond to anything in the back
end or in the database and there may be
hundreds of flavors to deliver. And so,
yeah,
representing that as static pages would
be
impossible, I guess.
So, that seems like a big advantage.
Yes, you're right there. I tried to give
you a trivial example with seasons and
yeah, there's only four of them, but
yeah, you could you could scale that up
to names of people or something which
could be theoretically infinite.
Okay, so we talked about routing and how
Next.js does that differently than React
by itself. Another concept, we've talked
about rendering, but is the difference
between client-side and server-side
rendering and what is Next.js providing
there or what is its opinion on which is
the better approach or which is which
approach should I consider in which
case?
There's a lot of interesting things to
touch on here. First, I think we should
probably define client-side rendering
versus server-side rendering and then
there's a third one which is called
static rendering, also called
pre-rendering. So, there's three kind of
ways to render an app. So, I'll I'll
I'll just touch on what each of those
are and then I'll go into the benefits
and drawbacks of each of them. So,
client-side rendering is kind of the
very first in the evolution of
single-page applications, client-side
rendering was was the first way of doing
things. By no means is it perfect, like
it represents some problems, and then
server-side rendering came along to say,
"Hey, we think we can solve those." And
then static rendering came along later
to say, "Hey, I think we can solve the
problems of server-side rendering." And
none of these things are kind of
perfect. So, basically, in a single-page
application, when you go to the front
page of the application, the very first
thing you're downloading is a piece of
HTML, and in that piece of HTML is just
a blank screen. There's nothing there,
but it says, "I need you to go get this
piece of JavaScript." Uh that's the most
important thing you need to do. So, you
start downloading a piece of JavaScript,
and the JavaScript starts to execute,
and then its job is to say, "Hey, I
wanted you to take that blank screen,
and I'm going to render something onto
it." And then your app is born. That's
client-side rendering. So, what's
happening is you download a blank page.
That's the HTML that you have. You run
the JavaScript, and voila, your app pops
up. Now, downloading the JavaScript is
expensive. The app it can be really
huge, and that's going to cost you
time, money, whatnot. The other big
problem is search engines. So, we all
care about getting our websites, uh
indexed by Google, and this isn't true
anymore. Google has solved this problem,
but in the initial days of single-page
applications, the Google bot would come
along, download your blank page, and it
wouldn't bother getting your JavaScript
and executing and running it. So, it
would judge your site based on this
blank page, which is pretty worthless.
And so, your your single-page
application's not going to do well in
Google, and that's a big problem. So,
server-side rendering was born. It was,
"Hey, we can do better than this. We can
actually render this this site, just the
front page, like the one page you're
looking for, we can render that on the
server, and so we won't send you down
blank HTML. We'll send you down fully
formatted HTML, and then we'll still ask
you for the JavaScript application,
which is the React app. You'll still
have to run the JavaScript. You're going
to boot up the application, and then it
does this process called hydration,
where it says, "Hey, we all we know
we've got components already rendered on
the screen. We've got HTML on the
screen." Hydration is saying, "Okay,
we've got this fully loaded app in the
background. We've already got HTML on
the screen. We need to merge these two
things together. We're going to hydrate
what's on the screen with our React
application so that we can now start
syncing things up. So, when people click
on buttons, React wakes up and says,
"Okay, I now need to render this
component. I now need to render that
component." So, this was like, "Oh,
great. Server-side rendering is going to
solve the problems of search engines."
And then Google came along and said,
"You know what? We updated our Google
bot, and now it can download your
JavaScript, and it can run the React
application, and you don't need to worry
about server-side rendering anymore.
We're good there." Now, I'm not sure
about other bots like Yahoo bot and the
Bing bot, and there's, you know,
thousands of search engine bots. But,
Google has told us they've unveiled the
secret sauce that yes, they will render
your React application and have have a
look at that code, and and they will
judge your website accordingly based on
that. So, we don't have to worry so
much. There's So, that's like one
argument away from having to do
server-side rendering. Server-side
rendering is
it adds a lot of complexity to your
application, cuz now in in your
JavaScript code, when you're writing
your application, typically you might do
things like I want to access a property
of the window object, which only exists
in the browser. It doesn't exist on the
server. There's no window object, cuz
there's no browser on the server. When
you're when you're rendering when you're
doing server-side rendering, you're
doing it inside of Node.js. There is no
browser. So, typically you have to have
a lot of if-else statements in your code
base to say like, "Hey, if I'm on the
client, and then I can access window and
do this thing. Else, if I'm on the
server, then I need to access the file
system and do this thing to to to get
the piece of data that I want." So, it
ends up making your application kind of
messy. And so, I should touch on the
third thing, which is pre-rendering or
or static rendering. And that's when
you take every permutation of every
piece of state that your application
could come up with on the back end and
you render it before any requests show
up on your web server at all. And then
when a request shows up to your web
server, you say, "Oh, you're looking for
this state of an application and you're
you're asking for it based on a route
that you've chosen and I already have
that state of the application rendered.
I've saved it to a static HTML file over
here. I'm just going to send that back
to you." And so, solves the problem of
client-side rendering in that you're
going to get you're not going to get a
blank white screen at the very beginning
and then you have to download some
JavaScript. You're going to get some
actual content and it solves one of the
problems of server-side rendering which
is that rendering on the server is
actually expensive. Rendering on the
client is expensive. Rendering on the
server just rendering in general is kind
of an expensive operation.
So, rendering on a on a server is is
expensive and I have a pretty good
horror story of how it actually took
down some web servers at one point.
Let's hear that although I want to be
clear of these three approaches,
client-side, server-side and I guess
static, which is Next.js enabling? Can
you do all three with React alone or is
which is Next.js providing, I guess?
Next.js gives you the ability to do all
three. It helps make this the
server-side rendering easier. It removes
some of the boilerplate stuff for you.
It can do all the the static rendering
for you and it depends on how you set it
up.
My preference is still client-side
rendering in most cases and then
pre-rendering for some other cases. I'm
not a huge proponent of server-side
rendering. And that's going to surprise
a lot of people because Next.js sells
server-side rendering really hard. You
know, we do this for you and it gives
you some benefits and there are some
benefits there.
But, some of the problems with
server-side rendering is your
application is not actually functional
and useful in the browser until you've
downloaded that expensive expensive
piece of JavaScript and you've hydrated
your application. So, yes, you will get
that first paint really quickly and
you'll see some content on the screen,
but nothing's going to work. None of
your buttons are going to work. Your
site's not interactive until you've
downloaded the JavaScript bundle and
hyd- hydrated that application. So,
there's a moment of frustration for the
for the user that happens there. And
you're staring at something and but it's
not working. And so, maybe you you solve
that with with loading screens and
whatnot. One of the bigger problems with
server-side rendering that I encountered
at a a fairly large company is that it
doesn't scale well or or we couldn't
find a way to get it to scale nicely for
high traffic sites. You have to realize
that to render React on the server, you
need to use Node.js. That's the only way
to run JavaScript outside of a browser
is using Node. So, depending on whatever
your server is, and we we didn't have
Node servers in our case, but even if
you did have a Node server, I think you
would still have this problem. So, first
of all, we didn't have a Node server.
Our our web servers were typically
running .NET sort of stuff. So, a
request would come in to say, "Hey, I
want this web page."
.NET would go, "Okay, I need to fire up
a Node instance. I need to say,
'Someone's looking for this route.'"
Node would have to fire up our React
application, render it, send it back to
.NET, and then .NET would send the
server-side rendered version of the page
plus the JavaScript application back
down to the client. So, right away you
can go, "Hey, there's there's this step
you have that's kind of expensive
getting in the way." And it's it's .NET
firing up Node
just to render a page and then sending
that back. So, let's just assume for
this example that we don't have a .NET
server. We're talking straight to Node.
So, Node is our web server. And a
request comes in and says, "Hey, I want
this page." Node says, "Okay, fine. I
need to boot up this React application,
do a render, and send it back to you."
The problem is that Node and all
JavaScript is single-threaded, which
means it can only do one thing at a
time, can't do anything else. Now, on a
high-traffic website, and I said renders
are expensive, remember, so you've got a
request coming in. Node says, "Okay, I
need to stop everything else, and I need
to handle the rendering of this
application." On a high-traffic website,
if another request comes in while doing
that render, then it has to wait, so it
gets queued up. And on a really
high-traffic website, like the one I was
working on, a couple hundred thousand
requests would show up during
the rendering of this React application.
So, now these couple hundred thousand
requests are waiting because there's
only one Node instance that can only do
one thing at a time. This is a big
scaling problem. So, to get around that,
you can scale up Node. You can run one
Node per core of CPU that you have on
your web server. So, you can throw money
at the problem and just increase the
number of web servers you have, increase
the number of cores on the web servers
you have. Uh but you end up getting into
round-robin problems. So, to do that
properly, you have to have some sort of
scheduler built into your web server
system saying, "Okay, I I need to find a
Node instance that's free,
and I'm going to send this request to
that Node instance. And then the next
request I'm going to send to the next
free Node instance that I have. And when
I finally run out of Node instances,
then I have to use some sort of queue."
This makes the whole problem way more
complicated. And all you're doing is
you're
What are you saving? Google can handle
your client-side rendered application
perfectly fine. And Google Bot is the
one bot you really need to care about in
in your website. So, that problem's kind
of been solved. Even if you are sending
down a server-side rendered page to the
user, they're still going to experience
this moment of frustration because they
still have to download your JavaScript
application in order for this static
page to become interactive and useful.
And so, at the end of the day, I made
the call of let's just get rid of
server-side rendering. It's it's adding
all these if else statements to our code
base, so it's making our code base
bloated and gross. We're not node
experts,
so we don't know how to scale node
properly in order to fulfill the needs
of a of a high traffic website. At the
end of the day, we went with client-side
rendering. I'm happy about that decision
and I I kind of and anytime anyone
suggests server-side rendering, I kind
of go,
"Ah, yeah, that's
maybe not such the greatest thing." I
mean, I know it's sold to you as like
the savior of of all the problems of
client-side rendering, but it comes with
a whole bunch more problems. So, I'm
going to stick to client-side rendering.
And I will do pre-rendering, but that
only works for for cases where you're
not going to have like a very
interactive dynamic page. So,
pre-rendering's great for blogs,
something like The New York Times or
something. If they're just printing up
news articles, they just need to render
that news article once. There's nothing
on that page that's going to change. So,
you just render it once using a React
system and then you can serve that page
statically. That's a great solution for
for those sorts of things, but it won't
work in like a chat application.
So, it sounds like there's a lot of
options and maybe the trade-offs depend
on the specific application, as usual, I
guess. One of the things you mentioned a
few times is sort of the size of the
JavaScript bundle or just the JavaScript
program that you have to download. And I
know another Next.js feature is code
splitting. Is that a different way to
address this fact that the page is not
ready to use if you're able to split
your code up?
Yeah, absolutely. Code splitting is
essential for every React developer to
kind of figure out and master. Now, you
can do this without Next.js, but Next.js
does it for you and makes it really
easy. Without Next.js, you have to
become a Webpack guru and Webpack is
kind of the old way of building React
applications and it's uh kind of
complicated framework to kind of master.
And you could also use There's something
called React Loadable and there's
another React module. So, there's a
bunch of different ways to do code
splitting. Before Next.js, I was using
React Loadable, which allows you to
define a component as a dynamically
loaded component which
inserts a split point into your
application.
Code splitting is basically taking your
React application which is rendered down
to a single giant JavaScript file and
breaking it up to say it doesn't need to
be one JavaScript file. It can be lots
of JavaScript files. There's no need for
me to download the entire website if I'm
only going to look at one page. I only
need the JavaScript that renders that
one page.
And so you use code splitting to achieve
that. You can let's see.
Next.js will come along and it will
cleverly decide, "Hey, these components
are mapped to this route and so we can
split them off and we know that if
you're going to this route you only need
these components. We'll package all that
up into one little smaller JavaScript
file and when you go to this route
you'll just need that small file. When
you go to the next route you can
download the next little JavaScript file
that you need." So you're making
essentially more network requests and
downloading more files but they're all a
lot smaller. The net effect is
you have a snappier, faster, seemingly
faster site because you're not
downloading
the entire world to look at one thing.
As long as we're talking about
optimizations related to performance,
there's another Next.js feature related
to image optimization. Is that something
you make use of?
Yeah, that's something. So when we
flipped our application over to the
Next.js one of the exciting things was
making use of the Next.js image tag
which offers a lazy loading feature for
you. So images are generally also
expensive things on web pages and like
the goal of a web developer is you're
trying to figure out how do I give you
the biggest awesome experience for the
least amount of bytes sent over the
wire. So images give you a big bang for
your buck like they look great but they
do cost a lot. And so you want to load
them lazily which basically means if
I've got a whole web page on the screen,
the bits off the screen is known as
below the fold. So, if there's any
images below the fold, I don't need to
actually download them unless I scroll
them into view. Or if I get close to
scrolling them into view, then maybe
it's a good idea to start downloading
them. Let's say I have a massive page
that's really, really long, and most
users never, ever get to the very bottom
of it. You don't need to load that image
that's hidden on the very bottom.
There's only like 2% of your users that
are ever going to get down there. And
so, lazy loading solves that problem.
So, those 2% of the users, they will
scroll down. As the browser approaches
getting to that image, Next.js will say,
"Okay, we need to download this image
now." So, it basically means you only
download the stuff that you are going to
look at and see, which is a big savings.
Next.js also
is able to take your images and size
them up accordingly for the screen size
that you're on.
So, potentially you'll have people
coming in on mobile phones, people
coming in on desktops. They're going to
want different sized images. Next.js
will handle that for you and make sure
that you're downloading the appropriate
one so that it fits into the right
place.
Before we move on to your migration
story, one last Next.js question. I'm
just wondering if there are any
developer quality of life features that
Next.js in particular provides that just
make sort of the day-to-day development
easier. I guess one I have listed here
is a fast refresh. Is that different
from React itself?
Oh, yeah. Okay, I could talk about that.
So, in terms of the developers' quality
of life, I would say Next.js gives you a
nice way to organize a React
application, a nice standard way to
organize a React application. So, if I
have a Next.js background and I come to
your Next.js app, I'm going to know
where to find things. There's kind of
some opinions on where things are
stored. Like, all the routes are stored
in a pages directory.
I know where to find configuration
stuff, so how to configure the website
itself. And one other really fantastic
thing that Next.js does well is called
hot module reloading or hot swapping, I
think it's also called. But basically,
when I'm developing a React application
locally on my own computer, I generally
have the code in my VS Code IDE or
WebStorm or whatever, and then I have
the site running live in a browser.
And as I make changes to the code, I
want to be able to re-render that in the
browser really quickly to make sure that
I'm coding properly. Hot module
reloading is a promise that React gave
to the world when React initially came
out, but it never worked well. All
right, I mean, it worked for a little
while and then it broke and it became
really frustrating. And basically, what
you want to happen is you want to be
able to load up your React application
in development mode so that it's talking
to a special little server in your
development environment, which is mapped
to the code in your IDE. So, the second
you change code in your IDE and you hit
save, boom, the React app goes, "Hey,
something's changed. I'm going to
re-render myself." And so, you get that
instant gratification of, "Oh, I changed
something in the code. I see it in the
React app. Hooray!"
That's called hot module reloading. You
don't have to rebuild your whole app
manually and relaunch the app to see the
change. It just happens right there for
you. Now, this came with React when
React first came out, and it always
notoriously broke in the first few days
of starting up a new React application,
and people were always scratching their
heads of, "Why did my hot module
reloading stop working?" And it was
usually cuz you installed some module
that did something funky and and it
broke hot module reloading. And I've I
spent so many hours chasing down, "Why
does hot module reloading stop working
in our application?" Next.js does I
don't have to think about it anymore. It
just works. And I can install modules
all day long, and I don't know what
secret sauce they've done in there, but
they've done something magical that just
makes hot module reloading working. It's
a huge headache when it doesn't work cuz
it's such a glorious feature for
developers to have. So, that's
definitely a bonus of Next.
Yeah, in my career, I've had the gamut
between essentially hot module reloading
even for a desktop application to the
opposite where it's extensive restart
time each time you make a change. And
it's certainly one of those things you
really enjoy when it's a short edit test
loop. It's really nice.
Yeah.
Okay, let's move on to your migration
story. You published a blog post moving
house to Next.js in October 2022
and we'll link to that in the show
notes. But let's talk first about what
application was this in general terms,
what was the scale of it, what did the
application do as far as databases or
images or what was sort of the
requirements, and then what limitations
you were bumping up against when it was
React only and kind of what pushed you
over the edge to make the move to
Next.js.
Yeah, so I'm working for a company
called BenchSci now and our flagship
product is something called Selector or
Reagent Selector. It's uh helps
scientists choose which sorts of
reagents they want to work with in their
scientific experiments.
That application, it was the first
application that BenchSci produced and
it was written in React and it was done
using vanilla JavaScript and it didn't
use Next.js. It was done before I
arrived at the company. It works well,
works fine.
It does the job. And then years later we
built another suite of applications
which we've just launched this past
year. We've just announced them. They're
called Ascend and they are a suite of a
a few more applications. And in building
those, they all kind of happened at the
same time and another developer before I
arrived at the company said, "Hey, let's
use Next.js for these uh for all the
benefits of Next.js. It's you know,
we're going to build a suite of brand
new React applications. We can do it all
kind of under one banner in Next.js.
We'll get all the benefits of Next.js.
We'll get the routing, we'll get the hot
module reloading, we'll get the
organization. We can do server-side
rendering if we want to." I arrived at
the company and quickly put that to bed.
And anyway, Next.js was great. Lots of
people could get behind it. We would
have some opinionated ways of how to
structure a React application. And so,
the new Ascend application was built
using Next JS. Hooray! But then we were
at this crossroads where we've got our
flagship application is still React, but
done in vanilla JavaScript, whereas our
new stuff was actually written in
TypeScript using Next JS. TypeScript is
a typing system that sits on top of
JavaScript. So, JavaScript is not a
typed language. It's a dynamic language.
And that basically means that when you
instantiate a variable, you can assign
an integer to it and then you can take
that same variable and you can assign a
string to it or an object to it. It's
dynamic. That's nice cuz it's flexible,
but it can cause a lot of bugs and it's
not really I would never recommend it
for like an enterprise solution. I'm a
big TypeScript convert. I think
variables should be really rigid and
statically typed so that they can't
change and you should be able to know
functions should know exactly what sorts
of properties or parameters are being
sent into them. What What is the shape
of those parameters and not guessing.
TypeScript solves all these problems.
Anyway, we wanted to take our bread and
butter flagship application, move it
into Next JS so it's aligned with all of
the other new apps that we've built, and
have everything under TypeScript, and
have everything under Next JS. So, that
was the goal of of the migration
situation. Before we had done this, we
basically had two apps. We had a Next JS
app and we had the selector application.
And we had to use an Express server so
that when you come hit our website,
depending on which page you went to, you
would get one of two single page
applications. You'd either get the
selector app or you'd get the the Next
JS app. And this of course is not
optimal because as you're moving through
the site, you could stumble upon a brand
new single-page application. Loading up
a single-page application, the worst
part about it is the initial load of the
application, the first 3 to 5 seconds of
loading that application up. Now, a
second on the internet is an eternity,
so you want to minimize those.
And so, having to go as you're moving
through a website and you hit a brand
new single-page application and you have
to load up a whole thing from scratch,
that's painful. So, it's not a great
user experience. We had to use an
Express server to decide, "Oh, you're
going to this route. Okay, well,
actually that means you no longer are in
this single-page application, you now
need to be over in this one over here."
These are all pain points for our users,
and we wanted to remove all of that. We
wanted to make the site feel a lot
snappier and faster. And we didn't want
to have a Frankenstein experience of
some of the stylings and components and
ways of doing things in one application
don't look 100% the same as they do in
the new application. So, as you're
moving back and forth, you'll notice,
"Huh, this button has square corners,
but this one has round corners. That's
odd, jarring." So, you want to be
consistent across your application. So,
there's another reason to do the
migration.
I was going to ask about the Express
server. Is that essentially routing but
at a higher level than within an
application, or what is the Express
server?
Yeah, so Express is a web server written
in Node.js, and basically we used it to
serve up whichever single-page
application you need. When you move
fully over to Next.js, you don't
necessarily need a web server at all to
make any decisions and you know,
dynamically serve you a piece of
content.
With Next.js, you can just serve up a
static file. You say, "Oh, you want this
route? Well, we're just going to give
you this single-page application. Oh,
you want this route over here? Oh, well,
we're just going to give you the same
single-page application, which is just a
static file. You're just needing to
download an HTML file and a and a bit of
JavaScript, and you're off to the
races." But in our old the way we had
the app set up before, the two apps set
up before, sometimes you'd have to flip
back and forth. So, oh, you're on this
route? Okay, there has to be some brains
thinking, okay, that route actually
means you need to go to this single page
application. And that route means you
need to go to this one over here. So,
because you need a piece of brain work
in there, you need to have a web server
in there that has to make a decision.
There has to be something that's doing
some logic. And so, that's what we use
the Express server for. We also had to
outfit links inside of the application.
So, let's say you were in the the old
JavaScript application, the non-Next.js
application, and you clicked on a button
that took you to the new one. That
button had to be clever enough to know
you're going to a route, it's not an
internal React route, it's not in my
application. You have to go up to the
Express server to figure out that you
actually need to switch over to a brand
new single page application. So, we had
to put logic in the app so that each
link knew, am I just re-rendering a
different state in my own application or
am I leaving the app and going to
another app? We could get rid of all
that logic and make the app a lot
simpler when we get everything under the
banner of Next.js.
So, this may or may not be related, but
I think you mentioned LaunchDarkly in
your post, which is a feature flag
management system, I guess. Did that
play a role in this migration in terms
of being able to selectively make these
kinds of decisions or selectively turn
on functionality?
Yeah, LaunchDarkly is it's typically a
split testing system
so that you can actually launch code
into your application without it being
turned on for all of your users. So,
just some of your users get to see new
code. And typically, people will use it
when they're rolling out brand new
features,
and they they want to figure out, I want
to present this feature to just a few
users, not all of them, and I'm going to
analyze how those users behave on this
new feature before I decide to roll it
out to even more users.
You can also use LaunchDarkly as a
feature flagging system. So, you could
essentially turn it into something that
says, "You are a user of this type of
role, therefore you get these sets of
features. We're going to orchestrate all
of that inside of LaunchDarkly,
and enable you to only see certain
things on your website. You could use it
in a blog if you have content that only
certain paid users wanted access to, you
could potentially use LaunchDarkly to
determine, do you have the feature flag
that enables you to see this content or
not?"
So, in terms of things that changed
switching this flagship application to
Next.js, did routing change, or what was
your method of doing routing before, and
what did you change to?
Yeah, the old legacy application had
React Router installed in it, so the
routes were programmatically inserted
into the application. Next.js handles
that piece for you, so you don't have to
programmatically put them in your app,
you just have to set up the right file
folder structure. And so, that's what we
had to do. We had to make sure that all
of the routes represented in the React
Router, and they were a little
convoluted, because you can have routes
inside of routes, and you can have
components that are introducing new
routes, and the old application kind of
had a bit of a mess there, where it
wasn't Usually, when you set up React
Router, I've seen it done where it's all
kind of done in one file, and all your
routes are defined in one place. But,
our legacy application didn't have that.
I don't know why, I wasn't around when
whoever decided to do that made that
decision, but it's a little tricky to
figure out what are all the possible
routes that this app accepts and can
render. We had to do a little deep dive
to figure out what they were. Once we
figured them all out, we then had to
transfer them over to Next.js, and place
them inside the pages folder. So, every
Next.js app has a pages folder, and
underneath there are all your subfolders
that map perfectly to your routes. And
one of the things that I like doing for
a Next.js application is I like to just
make sure that that pages folder only
really contains routing logic. And so,
when it finally gets to like, "Hey,
you're going to A/B/C," so C needs to
render a component. I call that a scene,
not a page. And the reason why I call it
a scene is cuz I used to work on an
application with a bunch of Android
developers, and their terminology is
scenes. So, they don't talk about pages.
Android apps don't have pages, they have
scenes. And because I'm also building a
application, but on the web, I said,
"Okay, I'll adopt that terminology. I'll
I'll call it scenes." Granted though, in
Next.js, it's under a pages folder. I've
just realized that now as I'm looking at
the folder structure of Next.js. So,
anyway, the point is, the thing I want
to mention is that in that pages folder
in Next.js, I feel like you should only
really have a routing logic in there.
When you get down to rendering the
actual c, the a/b/c, rendering the
actual c, what you want to do, what I
like doing is saying, "Hey, I want you
to render the c scene." Or, I guess I
should call it page now that I'm looking
at how Next.js names things, but
I want you to just render the c scene,
and I'm not going to actually place that
page rendering logic inside the pages
folder. It's going to import that scene
from our global components folder. So,
generally, a React application will have
a whole system of components, usually
organized in a nice global components
folder, and I would make a scenes folder
up there, or a pages folder up there, so
that all of my my rendering logic is in
one place, and all of my routing logic
is in another place. So, that's just a
nice way of kind of separating the
different folders and what they're meant
to do inside of Next.js.
Getting into some logistics, how did you
divide up the team to work on this
transition versus
maybe continual work on the new
applications? And how did you make the
actual transition? Presumably, it had to
be done in one step, or at least one
day.
Yes. Yeah, that was So, we have to
realize that we're taking a legacy
application, and we're merging it into a
new application, and both of those
applications are being worked on
constantly by a whole bunch of
developers all over the place. So, we
carved out a team to do the migration.
There was like four or five of us, I
think, and that was our our migration
team. And the first thing we did was we
set up a bash script, or maybe it was a
node script, that in our branch, it
performed the migration. It took
Actually, we probably did it as a node
script, now that I think about it, cuz
there was a lot of details that went
into doing that. But, we basically just
did a like a copy-paste move move files
around. Actually, we had to use get
move. You don't just copy-paste files
around. You actually have to get move
them. The reason why you need to do that
is because when you finally done the
merge, like on the day that you're
actually going to do it, and you finally
do the merge, and you push that back up
to your repo, there's going to be
developers out there that are still
working on old branches in the old
world, and as soon as you make your
merge, all their files aren't going to
be there anymore. They're going to have
moved over to somewhere else. So, you
have to use a get move operation to let
them know that when they rebase, and
when they pull down the contents of the
main branch, aka the migration, when
they merge that into their old
long-running branch, get is going to
say, "Hey, that file you were working on
over there, I'm clever enough to know
that it's moved over to here. Here's
where you go to find it." So, we're not
going to lose the development work from
those people. So, we had to incorporate
that into a node script, which we ran,
and it was sort of like our our dress
rehearsal script. We would perform that.
It would make the move, and then we
would go in and see, "Okay, what's
working and what's not working?" We've
taken all the code, we've moved it
across. It'll be amazing if it just
loads up perfectly on the first day. It
didn't, so. But, it was pretty close.
Like, you're taking React, and you're
putting it inside Next.js, which is also
React. So, there's a good chance that
everything's going to line up. Some of
the things that you we needed to work on
were transferring our image tags over to
the Next.js images, transferring the way
we used to do linking in the old app to
the Next.js links, which are a little
more clever, and then some configuration
stuff. So, sometimes links, like I said,
would be shouting out to an Express
server to figure out, "Do I need to
actually switch to a single page
applications. We don't need to do that
anymore. So we would have to add some
stuff in this dress rehearsal script
that would say, "Okay, I'm going to rip
that out and put it somewhere else."
Your runtime configuration sort of
stuff, so how you inject configuration
into the app depending on what
environment you're on. When we build our
application, it runs in our local
development environment, then it goes
into what we call mainline, which is
like a development environment where
everyone's changes meet each other for
the first time, and we find out what
happens and then from there it moves to
a QA environment and then to a staging
environment and then finally to a
production environment. And for each of
those environments, you need to inject a
bunch of configuration into the
application. That was done differently
for the two different apps, and so we
had to migrate those and merge them
together so that they're working
properly.
I think the post might have mentioned
public runtime config. Is that a type of
configuration for Next JS or for
Yeah, that's a mechanism for adding
configuration to a Next JS app. There's
a couple different types of
configurations. There's configuration
that you statically build into the
application at build time, but you want
to build your React application once and
then deploy it to different environments
and have it behave differently on those
environments because it's in that
environment. And to do that, you need to
inject public runtime configuration into
it. So it's saying, "I've built the
code. I'm not going to change the
contents of the code anymore, but now
that you're on the QA environment, you
need to talk to this server instead of
that server." And you do that through
public runtime config.
One of the last sections in your blog
post I think is called moving day. How
did that go when the final transition
was made?
Yeah, it was it was great and it was
stunningly great because we took a ton
of code, like thousands and thousands
and thousands of lines of code, that's
still being actively worked on, and we
moved it from A to B, and there were no
major blow-ups. Like we'd gone through
the dress rehearsal script so many times
and we'd done that move and we created a
special QA environment just for this
move. So we would do the move, we take
that branch that had everything merged
together, we push it up to this new QA
environment and we went through it with
a ton of manual QA folks and a lot of
developers went through there like
looking for different bugs and then
whenever we found one, we would
incorporate that back into our migration
script until we got to a point where
we're like, yeah, this is working fine.
The brand new like the QA server that we
have it running on,
we can't seem to find any bugs. So let's
go for it. And so we picked a date, we
announced to the whole company, okay,
we're going to do the migration. It's
probably going to take us, you know, 10
minutes to like do the merge and then we
need to deploy it which takes another 30
minutes and then we'd like to do a
sanity check for like an hour or two
just to make sure that nothing's crazy
and then you can go back to work. So we
we kind of picked a day, we told all the
developers,
just take a couple hours and do
something else for a second and we're
we're going to deploy this and see what
happens.
And it went great. Like there were no
major bugs. I was I really stunned. I
was like, wow, this we did such a good
job at building this nice dress
rehearsal script and the whole flow of
putting this up on a QA server and
testing it out before we unleash it upon
all our developers. And so yeah, it was
a big success, I'd say.
What were the concrete advantages that
most surprised you or that you were just
most impressed with in terms of the
transition as far as how the users
perceive the application, maybe
performance or otherwise or as far as
developer and continued development.
Basically, what was the net result here
for you guys?
Well, clearly like one of the big
advantages of doing this was that you
don't have this Frankenstein issue of
jumping between two different apps and
so you have this like loading problem
that happens as you're bouncing back and
forth. And in our suite of applications,
you would typically bounce back and
forth between these two things a lot.
And so having that jarring experience
was gone now. So the app felt a lot
faster. The other really big thing and
this I think was the major win is our
TTI went down by a lot. Now TTI is time
to interactive. It's what I think is one
of the most important metrics in any
single page web application that you're
building. And it's the time that it
takes for the first bite of that React
application to touch your browser until
the application becomes interactive and
you can actually click and do things on
it. You're aiming for that to be between
3 and 5 seconds.
And I think in the old days ours was up
to like 7 or 8 seconds or something. But
anyway, when we finally got everything
moved over to Next.js because of code
splitting, automatic code splitting.
That was the big thing. Our legacy app
didn't have any code splitting in it cuz
no one bothered to kind of figure out
it's a hard problem to solve and no one
bothered to figure it out. We got it for
free in Next.js. When we moved
everything over to Next.js, we saw like
a 40% improvement in our TTI, which is
actually a decrease cuz you want TTI to
be low. And that to me was like the
major win for us in that your
application loads a lot faster, which
gives you a
just a tremendous boost to your
usability of the application.
And going forward, I'm guessing it's an
advantage to have one style of
applications. So, that's going to make
development easier.
Yes, absolutely. So, now we can be more
consistent in our components. We can
share components. So, the legacy
application can now use components from
the new application. It's all just one
application now. So, there's a much
better ability to be sharing things back
and forth. We're going to be a lot more
consistent. Since this, we've now
developed a nice design system that
allows us to make sure that all the
facets of the application are using
components out of the design system. So,
we remain nice and consistent. And so,
now there's this nice uniform experience
across everything that BenchSci is
providing.
Let's start wrapping up. Can you speak a
little bit about the Next.js community,
the documentation, resources online, how
you feel that is, especially for someone
new to Next.js?
Yeah, I think Next.js is a very
successful and popular React framework,
probably the most or one of the most
successful React frameworks out there.
and that's definitely due to
documentation. You don't get to a good
place in developers' hearts without a
great documentation system. There's an
amazing Next.js developer community.
That's also a big attraction to why you
would want to use it. When you enter
into a new framework, you want to be
able to know at some point I'm going to
get stuck. How do I get unstuck? What
are the best ways of getting unstuck?
And the community for Next.js, the
documentation, totally help with with
making it feel like, "Yeah, this is a
safe move. Let's do it."
How about for someone starting on a
greenfield, brand new application? Are
they taking on more to start with
Next.js, or is that going to simplify it
if they use it from the beginning?
So, in the olden days, there used to be
this thing called create-react-app,
which nobody's using anymore, but it
used to be the standard, like, "Oh, you
want to make a React app? Just download
create-react-app and get that running,
and that will get you a React app up and
running nice and fast." I would never
recommend that anymore. And I would
totally recommend Next.js. So, now you
really just have to do like an npm
install next,
and it'll load up an application for
you, and everything just works, and
it'll give you a nice front page, which
of course you're going to change to suit
your own needs, but it's it's all there.
Great documentation to show you how to
put things together and move around. So,
yeah, Next.js is an awesome first
stepping stone for someone who wants to
make their first Next.js app. It'll help
remove a lot of the difficult, confusing
parts.
That sounds great. Thanks so much for
sharing all this with us. Is there
anything you'd like to say about where
to follow you or learn more about any of
this online, and we'll put any links in
the show notes?
Yeah, I mean, you can find me on Twitter
at Timothy Beamish, and of course the
link to the blog post is in there.
There's some more details of how we did
things. Feel free to reach out to me on
LinkedIn or on Twitter if you have any
questions about doing something like
this. I'm happy to help.
Thanks so much for talking to me today.
Yeah, thanks. It's been great.
This is Philip Winston for Software
Engineering Radio. Thanks for listening.
Thanks for listening to SE Radio, an
educational program brought to you by
IEEE Software Magazine. For more about
the podcast, including other episodes,
visit our website at SE-Radio.net.
To provide feedback, you can comment on
each episode on the website or reach us
on LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter, or
through our Slack channel at
SE-Radio.slack.com.
You can also email us at
team@se-radio.net.
This and all other episodes of SE Radio
is licensed under Creative Commons
License 2.5.
Thanks for listening.